TRISTAN SLATER

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

\$\ +1 778 922 3004□ hello@trslater.ca

trslater

in tristanslater

I am a software engineering graduate from the University of Victoria with more than 12 years of experience in the tech industry, working on projects for large companies such as Coca-Cola and eBay, teaching technology classes at the University of Alberta, and running my own freelance web development business.

EDUCATION

Sep 2016-Apr 2023 🔘

Victoria BC

Bachelor of Software Engineering (BSEng)

University of Victoria

- Cumulative GPA: 7.65 (~3.8)
- ML specialization
- o Graphics specialization

EXPERIENCE

Sep 2019-Dec 2020 🔾

Victoria BC

Front End Developer (Co-Op)

SunTracker Technologies Inc.

- Headed rebuild of greenhouse designer web app GUI
- o Headed rebuild of greenhouse designer app server in Python Django
- o Developed, deployed, and managed an NGINX web server
- Developed a Python interface for proprietary C++ library

Sep 2018-Aug 2019

Victoria BC

Software Developer (Co-Op)

Viral Bioinformatics Resource Center, Department of Biochemistry & Microbiology, University of Victoria

- o Developed, deployed, and maintained Java-based bioinformatics tools
- o Initiated several security and workflow improvements
- Headed rebuild of EC2 instance after attack
- Managed AWS EC2 instances
- o Initiated, defined requirements for ReactJS-based pilot project
- o Maintained WordPress website

Oct 2011-Sep 2013

Contract Instructor

Edmonton AB

University of Alberta's Technology Training Centre

- Developed and taught courses in web development
- o Taught courses in Microsoft Office and Creative Suite
- o Consistently received excellent feedback from students

May 2008-Sep 2016

Freelance Web Developer

Edmonton AB / Victoria BC

Self Employed

- Created websites for a wide variety of clients from realtors to storytellers
- Managed client project life-cycle from conception to maintenance
- Constantly developed and improved development process/toolchain
- Learned PHP, JavaScript, and MySQL to create custom interactive content
- Kept ended with relevant web technologies, frameworks, such as HTML5/CSS3 and WordPress

Aug 2004-Mar 2008

Creative Designer

West Kelowna BC

PureSafety Inc. (now part of UL)

- Embraced chance for learning and development
- Learned ActionScript to contribute to interactive learning activities
- Used scripts to automate production
- Worked with big names such as Coca-Cola and eBay

TECHNICAL COMPETENCIES

Languages		Libraries		Dev Tools		UNIX	
0	Python	0	FastAPI	0	Git/GitHub	0	Filesystem
0	JavaScript	0	Django	0	Docker	0	CLI tools
0	HTML/CSS	0	MkDocs	0	AWS	0	Bash
0	C/C++	0	React	0	Visual Studio Code		
0	Java						

CORE COMPETENCIES

HOBBIES & INTERESTS

Guitar

Hiking